Oleksandr Grytsenko - Curriculum Vitae

Profile

I am an outgoing person who enjoys a challenge. Combining strong technical expertise with a skill set of an experienced leader, I manage two separate teams working on different projects. As of now I work to enable, facilitate and nurture a variety of service desk solutions, based on various CRM and help desk applications as well as development of an eCommerce platform with strong ERP features. I have an extensive experience working abroad with different types of businesses



Personal information

as both developer and business analyst.

Current Location	Kharkiv, Ukraine	Date of birth	21 June 1982
Nationality	Ukrainian	Primary Language	Russian/Ukranian
Mobile	+38 050 3000 499	E-mail	grytsenko.a@gmail.com
Linkedin	http://ua.linkedin.com/in/grytsenko/		

Education

Master of Computer Science

September 2003 - February 2005

KNURE (Kharkiv National University of Radio Electronics)

Subjects covered:

General: Philosophy, Economics, Staff Managment

Occupational: Linux administration (Suse, Fedora Core), Web Development (Perl+Mysql), Software

development(C++), Systems and network analysis, Network protocols.

Diploma: Hardware development

Bachelor of Computer Science

September 1998 - July 2003

KNURE (Kharkiv National University of Radio Electronics)

Subjects covered:

General: English, Physics, Mathematics, Religion, Metrology.

Occupational: Network building, Turbo Pascal, Basics of Radio Engineering, Network protocols.

Training and courses

Calculus January 2013-May 2013 Coursera, certificate with distinction

ITIL, foundation September 2010 Knowledgeforit, Kiev, Ukraine

Machine Learning June 2013-August 2013 Coursera

CMMI training CMMI basic knowledge training including implementation of measurement and Ana

implementation of measurement and Analysis areas.

October 2007-May 2008, ProcesX, Medellin, Colombia

I have attended multiple 1-3 days conferences where I was introduced to Agile, Scrum, People/Project management technics and processes.

Skills and competences

Technical skills: • Technical engineering • Software development • Radio engineering

Computer skills: • Windows administration (2000/2003/XP/7/8) • Personal Linux station administration •

LAMP/WAMP extensive knowledge

Project Management Skills: Agile • Kanban • Waterfall • RUP

Programming skills: PHP 4 & 5 • XML • AJAX • SQL • HTML/CSS • JavaScript, Jquery,

Frameworks: • Symfony • Zend Framework • YII

Products: Kayako • ZenDesk • ERP • Joomla • Wordpress • WHMCS • Drupal • Shopify • osCommerce •

PrestaShop • Magento • Various other PHP products

Extensive knowledge of: ITIL • eCommerce • Business Analytics • Sales

Languages:

Russian/Ukrainian : Native English: Full business proficiency

Spanish: Have good writing speaking and understanding skills.

Work experience

May 2008 → To date Business Development Manager/Department Director - DataLink UK Ltd

Software development company, headquartered in UK.

Main activities and responsibilities:

Director of Support Systems department. Portals : www.zendesk-solutions.com www.zendesk-solutions.com May 2008 → to date

Responsibility:

- Creation of new business for the company from the scratch. Initially I was the only developer and sale person
- Account management and building partnership network
- Marketing strategy for the business
- Project Management, Sales, Business Analysis, department financial management
- Managing a development team of developers/sales/QA(total 15 people)
- Customer's requirement analysis, project documentation
- As a consultant I performed multiple ITSM integrations to different types of businesses around the globe.

Achievements:

- Over the years department has grown to 15 people
- Company has acquired over 1000 customers among them Mars, Emerson, MailRu, OB10, QNAP, Hepsiburada (#1 amazon like site in Turkey), Haya Water and others.
- Company become trusted implementation partners for leading helpdesk companies: Kayako, ZenDesk
- Brought lots of ideas about custom modules for supported products

Police labor union management software (location Belgium and Ukraine)
June 2011 – to date

Responsibility:

- Initial architecture for Labor Union management software
- System modeling and requirement analysis
- Understanding of Belgium's Labor unions law
- Development team Integrated Holiday Management, Members' Management, Legal Management processes into the system

WebRetail365 ERP system development manager (location UK and Ukraine) June 2009 – June 2014

Responsibility:

- Initial architecture and the core development of ERP system
- Customers company business processes analysis and integration of them into system framework
- Feature roadmap development and product lifecycle management
- Management of a team of 6 developers, 2 QAs and 1 technical writer
 - Ukflooringdirect was a project that I lead with my team for over 4 years. We integrated all business processes of a company into that system. Product management, goods in/out, supplier management, delivery management, customer service management, sales management and CRM.

Achievements:

- Complete ERP solution was created under my complete supervision
- Company received a new competitive product
- The product brought to the company a few big online retail customers
- Deployed the ERP system to multiple online businesses such as Ukflooringdirect, ApplianceWorld, Online-Shop.ie and others
- Formalized development and business processes for ERP department. Integrated Semi-Agile model into development lifecycle.

June 2007 → May 2008 Internship/Web Development - Soft Air LTDa

Software development company, was headquartered in Medellin, Colombia **Responsibility:**

- Software development
- Kayako modification. Customization Kayako's support suite to satisfy client needs.
- Kayako Modules. Creating custom modules.
- Custom built systems. Development of the system based on the customer requirements.
- Customers communication. Daly contact of the clients, project status report, customer's assistance
- CMMI requirements implementation. Implementing CMMI model to the company core.
- Company site support. Weekly update of the site, new features development

Achievements:

- Acquired good PHP development skills
- Acquired business analysis and project management skills
- Learned fluent Spanish language

August 2005 - June 2006 Technical support/Senior system administrator - Sbb-Invest

Agriculture Equipment sale company

Responsibility:

- · Windows 2003 server support
- 1C product support
- Web development
 - o www.sbb-invest.ru (2005)
 - o www.ssb-invest.inmak.biz (2007)
- Users technical support

Short list of projects either developed or supervised by me:

Ecommerce: Hatcountry.com, Nok200.com, ukflooringdirect.co.uk, atticusclosing.com, harrypotterexhibition.com, ogilvyprlondon.com, appliance-world.co.uk, board.com, supportia.no, Bikiniisland.au, gamegear.be

ITSM: Emerson, Haya Water, Hepsiburada, OB10, MailRu, FXpig, Support.Board.com, QNAP, Anritsu, Template Monster, Envato, Safe-Host, Securesupport, Securegroup, Buhl-data, Checkout.com, concep, Sage Asia